The untold story of the Rumble in the Jungle.
When We Were Kings is a documentary, tv movie,
history film directed by Leon Gast.
Muhammad Ali is 32 and thought by many to be past his prime.
George Foreman is ten years younger and the heavyweight champion of the world.
Promoter Don King wants to make a name for himself and offers both fighters five million dollars apiece
to fight one another, and when they accept, King has only to come up with the money.
He finds a willing backer in Mobutu Sese Suko, the dictator of Zaire, and the "Rumble in the Jungle" is set,
including a musical festival featuring some of America's top black performers, like James Brown and B.B.
Self, played by Muhammad Ali.
Self, played by George Foreman.
Self, played by Don King.
Self, played by James Brown.
Self, played by B.B. King.
Self, played by Spike Lee.
When We Were Kings is a 1996 American documentary film directed by Leon Gast about the "Rumble in the Jungle" heavyweight championship boxing match that was
held on October 30, 1974, in Zaire (now the Democratic Republic of the Congo) between world heavyweight champion George Foreman and  Muhammad Ali.
It features archival footage of celebrities, including James Brown, B.B.
King, and promoter Don King, in the lead-up to the fight and accompanying Zaire 74 music festival, alongside
interview footage of Norman Mailer, George Plimpton, Spike Lee and Thomas Hauser from the 1990s.
The film took Gast 22 years to edit and finance, but it was finally released to strong
reviews and won the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature of 1996.
The film explores themes of africa, boxer, black magic, world champion, zaire.